irvinehousingblog.com 2010-06-23

# Irvine Housing Blog - Irvine Real Estate and Irvine Homes

## Privacy Policy

The Irvine Housing Blog respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. The Irvine Housing Blog provides this Privacy Statement to inform you of our Privacy Policy and practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is used. We’ve structured our websites so that, in general, you can visit www.irvinehousingblog.com on the Web without identifying yourself or revealing any personal information. We make this notice readily available at the bottom of every Web page on our sites.

  1. Sites covered by this privacy statement
  2. Types of information we collect
  3. Children’s privacy
  4. How we use your information
  5. Who we share your information with
  6. Your choices
  7. Your privacy preferences and opting out
  8. Your information and third-party companies
  9. Access to and accuracy of your information
  10. Keeping your information secure
  11. Changes to this Statement
  12. Contacting us

**Sites covered by this Privacy Statement**

This Privacy Statement applies to all Irvine Housing Blog-owned websites and domains, and our wholly owned subsidiaries (“irvinehousingblog.com websites.“)

**Links to non-irvinehousingblog.com websites**

The irvinehousingblog.com websites may provide links to third-party websites for your convenience and information. If you access those links, you will leave the irvinehousingblog.com website. irvinehousingblog.com does not control those sites or their privacy practices, which may differ from irvinehousingblog.com. We do not endorse or make any representations about third-party websites. The personal data you choose to give to unrelated third parties is not covered by the irvinehousingblog.com Privacy Statement. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company before submitting your personal information. Some third-party companies may choose to share their personal data with irvinehousingblog.com; that sharing is governed by that third-party company’s privacy policy.

  1. **Types of information we collect**

This Privacy Statement covers personal information, non-personal data collection and aggregate reporting.

    * _Personal information_  
is information that is associated with your name or personal identity. irvinehousingblog.com uses personal information to understand better your needs and interests and to provide you with better service. Once you choose to provide us with personal information, you can be assured it will be used only to support your customer relationship with irvinehousingblog.com. We take seriously the trust you place in us. irvinehousingblog.com will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others. 
    * On some irvinehousingblog.com websites, you can order products or services, apply for instant credit, request information, subscribe to marketing or support materials, register yourself or your irvinehousingblog.com products, or apply for a job at irvinehousingblog.com. The types of personal information you provide to us on these pages may include name, address, phone number, e-mail address, user IDs and passwords, billing and transaction information, credit card information, contact preferences, educational and employment background, and job interest data. If you apply for instant credit, we will ask you to provide additional information such as salary, social security number and banking information. This information will be used by our financial services providers in determining whether to extend you credit.  
To personalize our websites, services or communications and improve our products and services, we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, and experiences with our products or services. Providing this additional information is optional. 
    * _Non-personal information_  
is data about usage and service operation that is not associated with a specific personal identity. irvinehousingblog.com collects and analyzes non-personal information to evaluate how visitors use the irvinehousingblog.com websites.  
Non-personal data we collect may include the pages visited on the irvinehousingblog.com websites, browser type and IP address. Most non-personal data is collected via cookies or other analysis technologies. irvinehousingblog.com Web pages use cookies and other technologies for data analysis and personalization services. irvinehousingblog.com also places ads on other websites that may use cookies. 
  2. **Children’s privacy**

irvinehousingblog.com is committed to protecting the privacy needs of children and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children’s online activities and interests. irvinehousingblog.com does not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 13 and irvinehousingblog.com does not target its websites to children under 13.

  3. **How we use your information**

irvinehousingblog.com uses your personal information to provide you with services and to help us better understand your needs and interests. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction or order, to communicate with you, to provide service and support, to update you on services and benefits, to personalize promotional offers and to personalize some irvinehousingblog.com websites. Occasionally we may also use your information to contact you for market research regarding irvinehousingblog.com products or services. We will give you the opportunity to choose your privacy preferences regarding such communications (see section 7, “Your privacy preferences and opting out”). Credit card information is used only for payment processing and fraud prevention. Sensitive personal information is collected only to facilitate our financial service providers’ credit decisions and will be shared with them only with your permission. Credit card information and sensitive personal data are not used for any other purpose by our financial services providers or irvinehousingblog.com and will not be kept longer than necessary for providing the services, unless you ask us to retain your credit card information for future purchases.

Personal data collected online may also be combined with information you provide irvinehousingblog.com through other sources such as product registration, call centers or public events such as trade shows or seminars.

Personal data given to irvinehousingblog.com may be transferred across state and country borders for the purposes of data consolidation, storage and simplified customer information management.

Non-personal data is aggregated for reporting about irvinehousingblog.com website usability, performance and effectiveness. It is used to improve the customer experience, usability and site content.

  4. **Who we share your information with**

irvinehousingblog.com will not sell, rent or lease your personal information to others. irvinehousingblog.com will not share your personal information with third parties except in responding to your requests for products or services. Your permission will be requested when you submit your information. irvinehousingblog.com shares customer information across irvinehousingblog.com-owned business entities and companies working on our behalf, but only as described above in “How we use your information.“

irvinehousingblog.com contracts with third-party service providers and suppliers to deliver complete products, services and customer solutions described in “How we use your information.” Suppliers and service providers are required to keep confidential the information received on behalf of irvinehousingblog.com and may not use it for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for irvinehousingblog.com. These service providers may change or we may contract with additional service providers to better accommodate our customers. irvinehousingblog.com will not share personal information with any other third parties without your permission, unless required by law enforcement action, subpoena, or local law.

irvinehousingblog.com or its related entities could merge with or be acquired by another business entity or some or all of their respective assets could be acquired. If such a combination or acquisition occurs, irvinehousingblog.com will make every reasonable effort to notify you in the event we share with the merging or acquiring entity some or all of your personal information to continue serving you.

  5. **Your choices**

irvinehousingblog.com gives you the choice of receiving a variety of information that complements our products and services. You can subscribe to receive certain product- and service-specific information and irvinehousingblog.com-wide marketing communications. irvinehousingblog.com-wide communications may include new product information, special offers, or an invitation to participate in market research. We give you a choice regarding delivery of irvinehousingblog.com-wide communications by postal mail, e-mail and telephone. You can make or change your choices via email at admin[at]irvinehousingblog[dot]com. We will make every effort to honor your preferences. This option does not apply to communications for the purpose of administering order completion, contracts, support, product safety warnings or driver updates.

  6. **Your privacy preferences and opting out**
    * _Non-subscription services_
    * irvinehousingblog.com will not use your personal information for a different purpose than the one stated when you provided your data. Examples of unrelated uses include sending communications about special offers, product information, and marketing messages.

    * _Subscription services_

To opt-out of receiving communications you have expressly requested (such as e-mail newsletters, software updates, etc.), use any of the following methods:

      * Return to the Web page(s) where you originally registered your preferences and follow the opt-out instructions
      * Write to the irvinehousingblog.com email address- be sure to provide your name, e-mail and postal address, and relevant information about your irvinehousingblog.com subscriptions and registrations
  7. **Your information and third-party companies**

We will not share your personal information with any third-party companies except for our credit card processing merchant.

  8. **Access to and accuracy of your information**

irvinehousingblog.com strives to keep your personal information accurate. We have implemented technology, management processes and policies to maintain customer data accuracy. We will provide you with access to your information, including making reasonable effort to provide you with online access and the opportunity to change your information. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity, such as a password and user ID, before granting access to your data. Certain areas of irvinehousingblog.com’ websites may limit access to specific individuals through the use of passwords and other personal identifiers.

The most effective way to view and change your personal information is to return to the Web page where you originally submitted your data and follow the instructions on that Web page.

  9. **Keeping your information secure**

irvinehousingblog.com is committed to protecting the information you provide us. To prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of the information, irvinehousingblog.com has in place appropriate physical and managerial procedures to safeguard the information we collect.

We use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. SSL encryption is designed to make the information unreadable by anyone but us. This security measure is working when you see either the symbol of an unbroken key or closed lock (depending on your browser) on the bottom of your browser window.

Credit card numbers are used only for processing payment and are not used for other purposes. As part of real-time payment processing, irvinehousingblog.com subscribes to a fraud management service. This service gives you and irvinehousingblog.com an extra level of security to guard against credit card fraud to protect your financial data.

  10. **Changes to this Statement**

If there are updates to the terms of irvinehousingblog.com’ Online Privacy Statement, we will post those changes and update the revision date in this document, so you will always know what information we collect online, how we use it, and what choices you have. For material changes to this Statement, irvinehousingblog.com will provide notification to affected customers.

  11. **Contacting us**

If you have comments or questions about our privacy policy, please send them to admin@irvinehousingblog.com.
